We know it's big. We measured.
Epic Movie is a comedy, adventure, fantasy film directed by Jason Friedberg.
When the Pevensie siblings each follow their own path, they
find themselves at Willy's Chocolate Factory.
Walking through a wardrobe, they discover the world
of Gnarnia, ruled by the White Bitch.
Meeting up with characters such as Harry Potter and Captain Jack Swallows, the newly reunited
family must team up with Aslo, a wise-but-horny lion to stop the White Bitch's army.
Edward, played by Kal Penn.
Peter, played by Adam Campbell.
White Bitch, played by Jennifer Coolidge.
Lucy, played by Jayma Mays.
Susan, played by Faune Chambers Watkins.
Willy, played by Crispin Glover.
Epic Movie is a 2007 American parody film written and directed by Jason Friedberg and Aaron
Seltzer, and starring Kal Penn, Adam Campbell, Jayma Mays, Jennifer Coolidge, Faune A.
Chambers, Crispin Glover, Tony Cox, and Fred Willard.
A parody of the epic film genre, the film references The Chronicles of Narnia: The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe,  The Da Vinci Code,
Harry Potter, Charlie and the Chocolate Factory, Pirates of the Caribbean, X-Men and  Harold & Kumar Go to White Castle.
Epic Movie was released by 20th Century Fox on January 26, 2007 and
received overwhelmingly negative reviews from critics.
It was a box office success, grossing $86.9
million against a $20 million budget.
The film explores themes of parody, crude humor, spoof.
The tone is lighthearted.